LAUREN **MILES**

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

Full Stack Software Developer with experience working with front-end and back-end technologies to create modern websites, applications, and automations to reduce manual workload. Works well in collaborative settings to accomplish common goals, bringing creative ideas and solutions to the table. Has a keen eye to detail to ensure work is completed to a high standard, while still accomplishing work within deadlines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TECH ELEVATOR, COLUMBUS, OH (REMOTE) - SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

FEB 2022 - MAY 2023

- Contributed to the BootcampOS application by adding new features and addressing support requests made by employees, students, and external clients using the software
- Architected and developed workflows, using Azure Functions, to automate the manual internal process of shipping label creation for student cohort laptops resulting in reducing workload from 2 days to just a few hours
- Collaborated with team to create application to automate student BootcampOS enrollment to replace manual process of gathering data and running scripts
- Instructed at Women Wine & Web Design event where 30 local women learned how to create a basic webpage using HTML and CSS, leading the instruction of course material and teaching participants the fundamentals of web development
- Resolved help desk issues reported by employees in a timely manner

NATIONWIDE CHILDREN'S HOSPITAL, COLUMBUS, OH (REMOTE) -SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

OCT 2021 - FFB 2022

- Supported the Marketing team by making updates to the main website framework using Sitecore
- Improved main website accessibility by ensuring pages and forms met requirements to pass audit at 100%
- Maintained existing internal applications by addressing bugs and support requests reported through company ticketing system

KIZAN TECHNOLOGIES, LOUISVILLE, KY (REMOTE) - ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE **DEVELOPER/CONSULTANT**

IUN 2020 - OCT 2021

- Contributed to the Custom Application Development team with rewrite of legacy portal application for Kentucky School Board Association that helped manage school board members, school board meetings and meeting minutes, and employment job applications for open positions
- Developed an internal application for Four Roses Bourbon to submit applications for internal funding proposals reducing total process time from multiple days to just hours
- Worked directly with clients to address any feature or support requests
- Exceeded career goals by being utilized as a full time developer within 2 months of employment

Detroit, MI (937) 329-1424 laurenmiles.dev@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- C#
- .NET Core
- **TypeScript**
- **lavaScript**
- Node.is
- Next.is
- React
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- **REST API**
- **MSSQL**
- PostgreSQL
- Microsoft Azure

EDUCATION

TECH ELEVATOR COLUMBUS, OH

APR 2020

Attended a 14 week .NET coding bootcamp learning how to create web-based software using C#.

CERTIFICATIONS

MICROSOFT AZURE **FUNDAMENTALS (AZ-900)**

SFP 2020

Demonstrated foundational level knowledge of cloud services and how those services are provided with Microsoft Azure.

LINKS

Ø github.com/laurenmilesdev

portfolio.laurenmilesdev.com